<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-20T14:45:20+01:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Web Dev Bev</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Training people to do accessibility reviews</title><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/01-2020/training-people-to-do-accessibility-reviews" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Training people to do accessibility reviews" /><published>2020-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/01-2020/training-people-to-do-accessibility-reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/01-2020/training-people-to-do-accessibility-reviews">&lt;p&gt;This was posted on the UK Government accessibility blog. In this post, I talk about the 'Intro to accessibility testing' workshops that I've been running at meetups and conferences across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2020/01/14/training-people-to-do-accessibility-reviews/&quot;&gt;View 'Training people to do accessibility reviews' on the UK Government blog&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This was posted on the UK Government accessibility blog. In this post, I talk about the 'Intro to accessibility testing' workshops that I've been running at meetups and conferences across the country.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accessibility profession project</title><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/01-2020/accessibility-profession-project" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accessibility profession project" /><published>2020-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/01-2020/accessibility-profession-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/01-2020/accessibility-profession-project">&lt;p&gt;This was posted on the MOJ Digital and Technology blog. I talk about a 6 month profession project on accessibility that I was placed on at the Ministry of Justice, in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://mojdigital.blog.gov.uk/2020/01/09/accessibility-profession-project/&quot;&gt;View 'Accessibility Profession Project' on the MOJ Digital and Technology blog&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This was posted on the MOJ Digital and Technology blog. I talk about a 6 month profession project on accessibility that I was placed on at the Ministry of Justice, in 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Motorbiking to Scotland and Back</title><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2019/scotland-bike-trip" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motorbiking to Scotland and Back" /><published>2019-09-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-09-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2019/scotland-bike-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2019/scotland-bike-trip">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I went to the Edinburgh Fringe festival by coach. When I saw the beautiful, winding, coastal roads out the window, I made a mental note to come back on my motorbike one day. I’m getting to do a lot of travelling around the various Ministry of Justice offices, at the moment, as part of a project I’m on. So when the time came to go visit CICA (Criminal Injuries and Compensation Authority), in Glasgow, I decided to combine the two things. Exciting! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The practicalities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adventure took a lot of planning. It’s 350 miles from where I live to Glasgow. I have a Honda CG 125cc, and my maximum range in one day is around 200 miles - if I have the full day for travelling, which I wouldn’t have, most days.  I figured if I was going to have a road trip, I’d have to make stop offs at various parts of the UK, to break it up. This actually worked out really well, as there are lots of parts of the UK that I wanted to visit.  So I sat down with the map on Booking.com, and broke it down into a few stages, and mapped out a rough route:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;Very rough sketch of route I took across motorways and overall route up to Loch Lomond and back&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/planning.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After booking the series of hotel rooms, I started to think about the actual riding. It was two weeks before the trip. I didn’t have enough thermals, or a bike suit that was protective enough. I also didn’t have a way of storing luggage on my bike, or keeping it dry (and two laptops would be in the bags). There was also an issue with the chain on my bike that needed fixing. Not exactly a trivial to do list! So the next two weeks turned into a bit of an eBay and Amazon frenzy, with a trip down to see my dad in Kent to get the bike chain fixed, and rummage around for my old waterproofs in my grandparent’s attic. It was pretty close: the final item arrived the day before the trip. I got ridiculously lucky on eBay with my new, more visible, better padded, comfy bike suit though, which I love to bits. In hindsight, more time for all of this would have been helpful!

&lt;h2&gt;On the road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 23rd of August, I loaded my bike up for the first time. I’d found some saddle bags on eBay for £40, bought a new bike suit on eBay at a bargain price of £100, bought a little tank bag for £30, a waterproof bag for my laptop at £20 and I’d got an absolutely huge waterproof jacket to go on top of everything else. All loaded up and dressed up, it started to look a bit crazy. I had rigorously checked out the reviews for everything I’d bought, but you never know how something will work for you personally until you try it. The rucksack strapped to the bag was so high that it required quite a bit of leg flexibility to get on and off of the bike, and I hadn’t done a test drive with the bike loaded up like that. London is a challenging place to drive, and I live right in the centre, so the first leg was a little trial by fire. Lots of people had told me not to do this trip, and seeing my tiny little bike under all this stuff, nerves were creeping in.  But, I set off, and after about 2 hours of paranoia about the saddle bags, I settled in to the ride, and made it to my first stop in Coventry.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Because I was staying with a friend for the shorter Coventry leg, the Saturday felt more like a normal trip than a road trip. Setting off for Middleton-upon-Teesdale was where it felt like it really began. It took me around 5 hours to make it the ~180 miles, and I arrived at Middleton-upon-Teesdale pretty late. I was pretty tired when I arrived! I then realised I’ve become more of a Londoner than I’d realised, when the pizza shop wouldn’t take card and I had no cash. This ended up in a fiasco of being unable to pay for a pizza they’d kindly already cooked for me whilst I was unsuccessfully finding a working ATM. By the next morning before leaving, I’d paid up via envelope through their letterbox though, and started my journey all the way up to Arrochar, near Loch Lomond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;Yorkshire dales in the evening, en route to Middleton-upon-Teesdale&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/yorkshire_dales.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pennines were en route, and gorgeous to ride through. The weather the day I was going through them was amazing as well, and so lots of other bikers were out. Normally down south, bikers tip or nod their heads at you when you pass, but as I got further north, it became more common for them to wave their hands at you instead. At first, I was so paranoid about my luggage falling off the bike that I thought they were waving at me to stop…! This was particularly heightened by that I had to go over a few cattle grids, which rattled the bike around a lot. After I realised it wasn’t a warning though, and adjusting to it, I decided I preferred it to nodding, and adopted it myself. There’s a lot of time to think when you’re on the road for 7 hours a day, and so I spent a lot of time wondering if that was an accent or dialect of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the hilly, sheep, stunning Pennines, I found myself back on the motorways. The M6 is not the prettiest of roads, and about halfway into the 180 mile ride that day, I did start to question what I was doing. I was too hot, and in my 5 years of being a biker, I’d only ever been too hot once before. My wrist was also a little painful, something I hadn’t factored in, and the motorway was not very inspiring. On top of that, city riding is the part I dislike the most, and my satnav took me directly through Glasgow to get up to to Loch Lomond, at a point where I was already tired from the previous 150 miles. Out the other side of Glasgow though, it wasn’t long before I was out riding alongside Loch Lomond! And it was definitely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;My motorbike parked up next to Loch Lomond&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/mimo_loch_lomond.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Scotland is beautiful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding a motorbike is different to being in a car. Because you don’t have the vehicle structure all around you, you’re a lot more connected and exposed to the world around you. You can smell farms as well as see them, feel atmosphere changes before it rains, and hear everything better. Sometimes these sensory things stick with you, and one of those memories I have from this trip is the cold coming off of Loch Lomond. As soon as the loch came into view, there was an immediate, sharp cold, refreshing wave of air. It was an unusually hot bank holiday weekend, which made it even more dramatic. I’ve never experienced that before, and it was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I saw of Scotland was beautiful. I spent a day in the Argyll forest, riding around all the lakes and coast I could find. Bikers are wonderful, and one couple saw me sat on a bench and chatted to me for hours. They invited me to lunch, which I unfortunately had to turn down, but they also recommended I take my bike on the ferry from Dunoon. I know it doesn’t sound like a big thing, but - oh my goodness - I was so excited. So, I put Dunoon in my satnav, and set off. On the way, I bumped into another friendly biker, who showed me a very rural, almost offroad route over a big hill, that was amazing fun (and a good test of my clutch control skills) It came out along the coast, and so I got to spend miles and miles riding around looking out at the gorgeous sea. Then I got to ride Mimo onto a ferry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;My motorbike on the back of a ferry, with coastal hills in the distance and lots of water turbulence behind the ferry&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/mimo_on_ferry.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my bike and I got from Dunoon to the proper mainland, I decided I wasn’t done with ferries, and Mimo and I went down to Largs, to get a ferry to the Isle of Arran. I thought where I grew up was remote, but some of the places I saw in Scotland was something else. Lots of school kids in uniforms got on the ferry to the Isle of Arran, and I got me thinking about how life on an island like that works, particularly in emergencies. It was fascinating, and so quiet that it was surreal - I went 10 minutes without seeing a car at one point. Two kids cycled past playing 80s music on a speaker at one point, whilst I saw pulled up and looking at the water, and I felt like I was in an old film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;Coastal road winding alongside water&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/coastal_roads.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept my eyes peeled for seals whilst going around the cost, but unfortunately didn’t see any. I love wildlife, and have also had a long-term goal to see a capercaillie, which is still unfulfilled. One day though, I did see a baby shrew running around on the road, and another day, some waterbirds airing their wings in the wind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;Lots of birds on an old abandoned, broken pier, and one of them has its wings held out, to dry them in the wind&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/bird_on_pier.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Rainier days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then made my way to Glasgow, to spend a couple of days with CICA, before going back to travelling. On the Thursday after work, I had to go through Galloway forest, to stay on the coast the other side. I was tired after the days at work, and hadn’t quite factored this in when planning the 90 mile ride. Because I was tired, it took me a while to get my head into the riding, and it didn’t help that about 3 miles into the roads, police vans pulled out of nowhere to block the roads off for an incoming protest, right in front of me. This spooked me, and from that point on road markings then got a little faded and hard to read, and the satnav took me on a very strange route through lots of estates, presumably to shave a couple of miles off of the 90 mile trip (or just to spite me, which it does sometimes). That ended up being the better part of that trip, though, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 hour in, when I got to the forest, it started to rain, and the windchill set in. Because I’d been tired, and not with it when I set off, I’d not put on enough thermals. Galloway forest is also one of the UK’s dark spots, and with rainclouds overhead, it started to get very dark at 7pm. I was cold, it was windy, and the roads were also incredibly quiet to the point of unnerving. The satnav also dumped me out on a really long, rural, single lane road, that was covered in sheep. When I was a teenager, I ended up having to sit through a lot of horror films, and that stuff never leaves your head (has anyone else seen Black Sheep?) So I was cold, having wrist pain flair ups, and getting a bit scared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been really stubborn about not telling anyone where I was going or what I was doing (I’m super stubborn and independent in general). Lots of people had said it wasn’t safe, and I have been told before that it’s not safe to motorbike alone as a woman. I’d decided to completely ignore all of this, out of a suspicion that there was sexism (either subtle or not so subtle) in this advice - but as I was freezing cold, in a very isolated part of forest, and still 30 miles away from a random hotel I’d found on the internet, that started to feel like a not-so-sensible decision. I got to the hotel okay (no encounters with zombie sheep or tool-wielding psychopaths) and warmed up with a hot water bottle before long, but it was a bit sobering. That night, rain pounded the windows and weather warnings for the following day were being flagged up on BBC Weather. I locked the bedroom door, curled up in my bed and sheepishly sent my planned locations to someone else, for peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;View from hotel room window of rain and a lot of flat empty land stretching out into the distance&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/creetown.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief bit of sun came out the next morning, and I practically ran out to the bike to set off - I had 220 miles to go that day, and weather warnings were still in force. The sun lasted about 15 minutes, and was then followed by about 3 hours of rain. Weirdly though, I found this day a lot less stressful. It took 7 hours, but my waterproofs did their job, it was full daylight with lots of other vehicles around, and all of my luggage waterproofing survived the rain. This stop-off was Buxton, and I was in for a pleasant surprise, because Buxton is beautiful. There was a park with geese in, an opera house(!), and a beautiful tea room that I had a huge piece of cake in the next day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image blog__image--side-by-side&quot; alt=&quot;Huge piece of summer fruits meringue and teapot in cafe&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/buxton_cake.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image blog__image--side-by-side&quot; alt=&quot;Gaggle of geese in Buxton park near the park lake&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/buxton_geese.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Buxton was sad, as it was the last leg of the holiday. After a brief detour to some friends near Walsall, I made the final leg back home, to London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I clocked around 1,200 miles across the trip, which was waaaay longer than anything I’d ever done before. Lots of people said it would be too dangerous, but if anything,  it did me a lot of good. I’m not always super confident in myself, and I wanted to prove to myself that I could do something like this. It was on me to get my bags off the bike and into the hotel, and to load the bike up safely, and to make sure I had proper breaks whilst riding, but still make sure that I made it to my paid-for hotel destinations. My failures were my own, but my successes were too, and I learnt a lot about myself in the process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s to more trips! I’m now thinking of planning a trip to either Wales or Cornwall, next Spring or early Summer, and making it a regular thing! I might even branch out to camping… (probably not I like proper duvets and mattresses too much)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; alt=&quot;Legs of author wearing bike trouser leathers and boots, with helmet next to boots, surrounded by heather and looking out over Loch Lomond&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-photos/bike_boots_and_loch_lomond.jpg&quot; /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A few years ago, I went to the Edinburgh Fringe festival by coach. When I saw the beautiful, winding, coastal roads out the window, I made a mental note to come back on my motorbike one day. I’m getting to do a lot of travelling around the various Ministry of Justice offices, at the moment, as part of a project I’m on. So when the time came to go visit CICA (Criminal Injuries and Compensation Authority), in Glasgow, I decided to combine the two things. Exciting!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accessibility Resources</title><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/05-2019/accessibility-resources" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accessibility Resources" /><published>2019-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/05-2019/accessibility-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/05-2019/accessibility-resources">&lt;p&gt;As it’s Global Accessibility Awareness, I’m sharing a list of accessibility resources that I regularly refer to. Happy reading, watching and listening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/accessibility-for-everyone&quot;&gt;'Accessibility for Everyone' by Laura Kalbag&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This is a great introduction to accessibility as a topic. I highly recommend it as the first thing you read!&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.smashingmagazine.com/products/inclusive-design-patterns-by-heydon-pickering-ebook&quot;&gt;‘Inclusive Design Patterns’ by Heydon Pickering&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;I am a huge fan of Heydon Pickering and his accessibility work, and Inclusive Design Patterns is a book that I regularly go back to. Brilliant introduction to accessibility and how to implement things well, with lots of HTML guidance.&lt;/p&gt;	
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Webinars and newsletters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://a11yweekly.com/&quot;&gt;A11y Weekly&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;I now regularly look forward to these weekly newsletters! They include a collection of really interesting articles from all over the internet. I’ve learnt a huge amount from these in a very short space of time.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://abilitynet.org.uk/free-resources/webinars&quot;&gt;AbilityNet Webinars&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;The quality of these webinars from AbilityNet are amazing! These people are experts in this field and it really shows. I highly recommend giving their talks a listen to.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h2&gt;			
&lt;ul&gt;			
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2017/02/24/what-we-found-when-we-tested-tools-on-the-worlds-least-accessible-webpage/&quot;&gt;‘What we found when we tested tools on the world’s least-accessible webpage’, GOV.UK accessibility blog&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;GDS did a fantastic piece of research into the effectiveness of automated testing. They created a very inaccessible website and ran a variety of automated tools. Spoiler; the top tool could only get 40% of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/projects/million/&quot;&gt;The WebAIM 1 million&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This is an amazing and slightly horrifying study that WebAIM completed this year. They took the top 1 million websites and ran an automated testing tool over their home pages. As well as it being a brilliant piece of research, they’ve also documented how they went about it really well. &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;		
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://alphagov.github.io/wcag-primer/#what-is-wcag-2-1&quot;&gt;GOV.UK WCAG 2.1 Primer&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This guide does a nice job of breaking down the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines into slightly more readable language, but still links back to them. It also contains a nice checklist of questions you can ask yourself throughout the process of building anything.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://adrianroselli.com/2017/11/a-responsive-accessible-table.html&quot;&gt;'A Responsive, Accessible Table' by Adrian Roselli&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;Whilst this is a bit niche, I had to include it because it’s such a beautiful illustration of how complex accessibility problems can be solved really elegantly. I really love pieces of writing like this.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oG_cYElSZwM&quot;&gt;‘Accessibility is more than just supporting screen readers’ by Seren Davies&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This talk is a fantastic introduction to accessibility, and how broad it is. Seren does a fantastic job of talking about different issues and some practical solutions, and also exploring the cognitive side of accessibility too.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/projects/screenreadersurvey7/&quot;&gt;'Screen Reader User Survey #7' by WebAIM&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This is a really great resource for checking that you’re testing with the most popular screen readers, and with the right browser combination. It’s worth noting though that this is a survey of everyone, and the user group for what you are creating might be different.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a fraction of the awesome resources out there. if there’s anything that you refer to as well on a regular basis, let me know! I’d love to hear about what you find useful too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As it’s Global Accessibility Awareness, I’m sharing a list of accessibility resources that I regularly refer to. Happy reading, watching and listening!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Geese Games</title><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2018/building-geese-games" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Geese Games" /><published>2018-09-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2018/building-geese-games</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2018/building-geese-games">&lt;p&gt;I got into a general life slump recently, and so to try and cheer myself up more, I’ve taken up building fun projects. I joined this industry because I wanted to build things, but I found that I got so carried away with organising coding events for others, I'd not made time for myself. I started ‘Geese Games’ last year, but I only really got as far as designing a colour scheme and general layout. I got a bit intimidated by the quiz functionality, so sheepishly put it to one side. This meant that the design was already in place though, and that I couldn't get caught up in fussing over design too much. So I figured this would be a good starting point!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why geese? I really like geese, and I wanted something super silly, so that I’d not end up taking it too seriously. So I intentionally made a slightly ridiculous design and picked out some pretty odd types of geese, and got stuck in. It got a bit intense; at one point I got such tech tunnel vision that I accidentally put one goose type in as ‘Great White Frontend Goose’, went around telling people that there really was such a thing as a 'great white frontend goose and then later realised I'd actually just made a typo. Little bit awkward... But it has been good intense, and I've had so much fun with this project! Building it has made me pretty happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Techwise, it’s gone great so far. I’ve really enjoyed the freedom of getting to choose both the tech and the general direction. Having a fun project with a series of small, fun goals also distracted me from my normal imposter syndrome of ‘oh god I should be able to do this JS exercise why can’t I’. I’ve gotten to play around with lots of new things that I’d have otherwise not have used, as well as things I already knew, and had a lot of fun! I've written up key learnings below to wrap up the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;React&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quiz like this definitely doesn’t need React, but I wanted a reason to play with it. I knew React from my day job, but it’s been a while since I last got to use it and I wanted to practise it more. I’m a little uncertain on how well React and accessibility mesh together, and wouldn't use it for everything, but it is a nice tool to develop with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start, the quiz was purely visual, as it was just a React exercise. Halfway through the project though, I decided I also wanted to explore how to incorporate a11y into this. I had a think about how to do this, and decided to add an alternate screen reader version of the quiz, whereby the alt text of the goose quiz image lists facts about the goose. This required getting more data, because at that point in time, each goose description was one big chunk of text copied from Wikipedia which included sporadic references to the actual goose name (which was both a little unstructured and would have also ruined the quiz). So I researched things like ‘weight’ and ‘uk population’, added this to the goose data, displayed this on the detailed goose info pages, and then created new alt tags specifically for the goose quiz page image that summarised this information. A side bonus of creating this screenreader version was that the information on the detailed geese pages became more structured, which benefits everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;React Router&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d not deployed a React app to GitHub before this project, had assumed it would be a bit more straightforward than it was, so I learnt a lot here. One thing that caught me up was having to use &amp;#60;HashRouter&amp;#61; instead of &amp;#60;BrowserRouter&amp;#61;. I don’t like the hash appearing in the browser, so one thing I wanted to do was switch to a Page Enum situation. I ended up passing data through the router across pages though, and I’m not sure how I’d do this without Router anymore. So that’s something else to work on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Styled Components&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jo Frank ran a introductory workshop on styled-components at uncodebar 3 in 2017. It was a great workshop and afterwards I wanted to carry on playing with it, so I put it in this project. I’m still undecided about it; I don’t like the randomly generated classnames that get put into the DOM, but I do like how quick it makes changing CSS, because it’s right there in front of you in your component. I'm still on the fence when it comes to projects like this. Having said that, I know from my dayjob that it can come in handy when you’re doing more complicated things with JS and CSS, so I would probably be much more pro using it in a more complex project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Govuk-react&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UKHomeOffice/govuk-react/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;govuk-react&lt;/a&gt; has been one of my favourite parts of the project. I absolutely love the GOV.UK Design System, and hadn’t known there was a React version that could be pulled in. I stumbled across it when having a play around with getting the non-React version, and got up and running with it very quickly. I will definitely be using this again in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;ES6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't do a great deal of JavaScript in my day job at the moment, and so a big reason for wanting to do this project was to get to do more. There isn't anything particularly advanced in this project, JavaScript-wise, but it was all good practise. In particular, for some reason, I’ve always had a mental block with the ES6 map stuff. I’ve come across it several times in several different projects but every time I’ve really struggled to get my head around it. This project has been the first time that I’ve felt like I’ve properly understood it though. I’m not saying I could now knock out a map function on a napkin in an internet-less field somewhere, but I’m still happy with this small breakthrough!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Things left to do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some things I want to do. I want to tidy up some of the React structure and JS, and in the process add in Redux. It doesn't necessarily need Redux, but I'd like to practise Redux. Another thing; the site isn't particularly mobile responsive at the moment, which is also something I want to improve, and the CSS could be improved a lot. I have plans for something else I want to work on next, but I'm sure I'll dip into the project here and there though over the next few weeks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Thanks yous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thank you to the people who’ve helped me out with this project along the way, either with technical advice, moral support or project suggestions: Alex Bokii, Pete West, &lt;a href=&quot;https://henryblyth.com/&quot;&gt;Henry Blyth&lt;/a&gt;, Marilyn Magnusen and Bob Whitehall.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I got into a general life slump recently, and so to try and cheer myself up more, I’ve taken up building fun projects. I joined this industry because I wanted to build things, but I found that I got so carried away with organising coding events for others, I'd not made time for myself. I started ‘Geese Games’ last year, but I only really got as far as designing a colour scheme and general layout. I got a bit intimidated by the quiz functionality, so sheepishly put it to one side. This meant that the design was already in place though, and that I couldn't get caught up in fussing over design too much. So I figured this would be a good starting point!.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 Oxford Indie Web Camp</title><link href="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/05-2018/2018-oxford-indie-web-camp" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 Oxford Indie Web Camp" /><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/05-2018/2018-oxford-indie-web-camp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/05-2018/2018-oxford-indie-web-camp">&lt;p&gt;The Indie Web movement is a movement all about content ownership, in the current times of Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and so on. It has been something I’ve been interested in ever since hearing &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com&quot;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt; talk about it at a conference last year. So I was super excited to hear that the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://polytechnic.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Garrett&lt;/a&gt; was organising an Indie Web Camp in Oxford! Here’s a summary of what I did over the two days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Day One&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day one was spent at the wonderful White October offices, with snacks provided by Haybrook. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Level 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got Level 1 set up! This involves setting up indie web sign-in, which allows you to use your own website to log in to things. It’s where you create a two-way link between your own personal site and other sites like GitHub/Twitter etc. To do this, make sure that your site has a link to your profiles on this sites with rel=&quot;me&quot; in the mark-up, and that there is a link back to your personal site on those other sites. Once you've pushed it live, you can check the links at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiewebify.me/&quot;&gt;IndieWebify.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Level 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level 2 is about formatting your content for other sites, and letting other people know you’ve referenced their content with webmentions. Formatting your content for other sites involves micro formats. Microformats are semantic classes that you can add onto your HTML that allow for data to be picked up by other things. You add them to blog posts and it helps things pick out the data in a meaningful way. Webmentions are where you link to other people’s content and notify them that you’ve done this. I have to say, I struggled to get my head around how this actually worked, but Garrett was very patient, and helped me map out a little diagram to get my head around the system. Because my site is a static site on GitHub pages, I couldn’t figure out any ways of doing this with any kind of tooling, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danq.me/&quot;&gt;Dan Q&lt;/a&gt; helped me out with the command line curling you need to do instead. That was pretty cool! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Things Implemented&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went off piste a little bit after this, because I got super carried away with webmentions. I set up &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmention.io/&quot;&gt;webmentions.io&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/&quot;&gt;brid.gy&lt;/a&gt; for collecting them, and then got to work writing some JavaScript to collect my webmentions and display them on my Geese Games blog post. By the end of day one, I managed to get a face wall of people who’d liked my Tweet about my &lt;a href=&quot;https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2018/building-geese-games.html&quot;&gt;Geese Games blog post&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of the blog post, which was pretty cool! It wasn’t particularly ordered or filtered though, so I decided to try and tackle that the next day. Another thing on my to do list for day two was &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On day two, because of rain, we decided to all work from home - I unfortunately didn’t get the message until turning up at the office because I didn't think to check beforehand, but it worked out alright because I then went for a coffee with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marcus-povey.co.uk&quot;&gt;Marcus&lt;/a&gt; and worked from various food places on Cowley road for a bit which was lovely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Working with APIs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I started pulling in data from webmentions.io, and today I formatted it nicely. At the start of the day, the my fetch was an inline script that was pulling in the first 20 twitter likes. By the middle of the day, I had it all formatted out so that the fetch request pulled in the past 100 mentions, and filtered them into different sections on the page against ‘Twitter like’, ‘Twitter retweet’, ‘Repost’ and ‘Twitter reply’. I moved this script out into it’s own file, refactored it and made it reusable. One thing I learnt was how to chain parameters in an API call - you need to put &amp; in between each different parameter! That tripped me up for a bit, but now I know!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Webmention curling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d referenced &lt;a href=&quot;https://henryblyth.com/&quot;&gt;Henry&lt;/a&gt; on my blog post and so I wanted to send him a web mention. It took a while to get it to work, and we were a bit stuck for a little while, but in the end Garrett realised it was because it was missing a trailing / at the end of one of the URLs - then it worked! Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;DOM Manipulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I’d figured out how to filter out the different types of web mention, I decided that I wanted my JavaScript to create the social media sections. This way, I could reply on the script to generate the relevant sections, and would also know if that if the user hadn’t enabled JS, redundant headers wouldn’t be appearing on the screen. Getting the relevant HTML generated wasn’t too hard, but getting the sections to render in a set option proved to be a bit trickier. In the for loop, the sections were being generated in order of what appeared in the array first, so I couldn’t rely on a fixed order that way. In the end, I did this with a separate for loop for each section, and arranged these in the order I wanted the sections to appear, at the top of the fetch. There is probably a more elegant way of doing this, but it works for now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a super fun few days, and I’m pretty pleased with what I’ve achieved! If you check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://webdevbev.co.uk/blog/09-2018/building-geese-games.html#social-media-responses&quot;&gt;Social Media section of my Geese Games blog post&lt;/a&gt;, you can see what I did over the two days. I didn’t get to putting my blog on Jekyll, but I’ll carry on with that another time. In case you’re interested in having a go yourself, I've included some links below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Useful links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Wiki for the indi webmovement: &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;https://indieweb.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Webmention tool for static websites: &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmention.io/&quot;&gt;https://webmention.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Webmention tool for Twitter for static sites: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gy/&quot;&gt;https://brid.gy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Talk by Adactio on the Indie Web: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/VvYK-K0jWng&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/VvYK-K0jWng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://polytechnic.co.uk/blog/2018/09/indiewebcamp-oxford-day-1&quot;&gt;Garrett's blog post about Day 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Indie Web movement is a movement all about content ownership, in the current times of Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and so on. It has been something I’ve been interested in ever since hearing Jeremy Keith talk about it at a conference last year. So I was super excited to hear that the wonderful Garrett was organising an Indie Web Camp in Oxford! Here’s a summary of what I did over the two days:</summary></entry></feed>