<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-23T23:30:38+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Web Dev Bev</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Accessibility Resources - Blog || Web Dev Bev</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/05-2019/accessibility-resources" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accessibility Resources - Blog || Web Dev Bev" /><published>2019-05-16T17:59:13+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T17:59:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/05-2019/accessibility-resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/05-2019/accessibility-resources">&lt;div class=&quot;background&quot;&gt;
	&lt;article class=&quot;h-entry&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalaccessibilityawarenessday.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blog__image&quot; src=&quot;./gaad-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visit the Global Accessibility Awareness Day website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog__title p-name&quot;&gt;Accessibility Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;p class=&quot;blog__date&quot;&gt;Published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://webdevbev.co.uk&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; class=&quot;p-author h-card&quot;&gt;Beverley Newing&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time class=&quot;dt-published&quot;&gt;16/05/2019&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;e-content&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;As it’s Global Accessibility Awareness, I’m sharing a list of accessibility resources that I regularly refer to. Happy reading, watching and listening!&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/accessibility-for-everyone&quot;&gt;'Accessibility for Everyone' by Laura Kalbag&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This is a great introduction to accessibility as a topic. I highly recommend it as the first thing you read!&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.smashingmagazine.com/products/inclusive-design-patterns-by-heydon-pickering-ebook&quot;&gt;‘Inclusive Design Patterns’ by Heydon Pickering&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;I am a huge fan of Heydon Pickering and his accessibility work, and Inclusive Design Patterns is a book that I regularly go back to. Brilliant introduction to accessibility and how to implement things well, with lots of HTML guidance.&lt;/p&gt;	
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Webinars and newsletters&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://a11yweekly.com/&quot;&gt;A11y Weekly&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;I now regularly look forward to these weekly newsletters! They include a collection of really interesting articles from all over the internet. I’ve learnt a huge amount from these in a very short space of time.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://abilitynet.org.uk/free-resources/webinars&quot;&gt;AbilityNet Webinars&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;The quality of these webinars from AbilityNet are amazing! These people are experts in this field and it really shows. I highly recommend giving their talks a listen to.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h2&gt;			
			&lt;ul&gt;			
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://accessibility.blog.gov.uk/2017/02/24/what-we-found-when-we-tested-tools-on-the-worlds-least-accessible-webpage/&quot;&gt;‘What we found when we tested tools on the world’s least-accessible webpage’, GOV.UK accessibility blog&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;GDS did a fantastic piece of research into the effectiveness of automated testing. They created a very inaccessible website and ran a variety of automated tools. Spoiler; the top tool could only get 40% of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/projects/million/&quot;&gt;The WebAIM 1 million&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This is an amazing and slightly horrifying study that WebAIM completed this year. They took the top 1 million websites and ran an automated testing tool over their home pages. As well as it being a brilliant piece of research, they’ve also documented how they went about it really well. &lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;		
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://alphagov.github.io/wcag-primer/#what-is-wcag-2-1&quot;&gt;GOV.UK WCAG 2.1 Primer&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This guide does a nice job of breaking down the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines into slightly more readable language, but still links back to them. It also contains a nice checklist of questions you can ask yourself throughout the process of building anything.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;http://adrianroselli.com/2017/11/a-responsive-accessible-table.html&quot;&gt;'A Responsive, Accessible Table' by Adrian Roselli&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;Whilst this is a bit niche, I had to include it because it’s such a beautiful illustration of how complex accessibility problems can be solved really elegantly. I really love pieces of writing like this.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;h2 class=&quot;blog__subtitle&quot;&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oG_cYElSZwM&quot;&gt;‘Accessibility is more than just supporting screen readers’ by Seren Davies&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This talk is a fantastic introduction to accessibility, and how broad it is. Seren does a fantastic job of talking about different issues and some practical solutions, and also exploring the cognitive side of accessibility too.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;
					&lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/projects/screenreadersurvey7/&quot;&gt;'Screen Reader User Survey #7' by WebAIM&lt;/a&gt;
					&lt;p class=&quot;blog__link-description&quot;&gt;This is a really great resource for checking that you’re testing with the most popular screen readers, and with the right browser combination. It’s worth noting though that this is a survey of everyone, and the user group for what you are creating might be different.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;This is just a fraction of the awesome resources out there. if there’s anything that you refer to as well on a regular basis, let me know! I’d love to hear about what you find useful too.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-media-responses&quot;&gt;Responses&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to interact with this blog post, head on over to the Tweet about it:&lt;/p&gt;	
		&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/GlobalAccessibilityAwarenessDay?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#GlobalAccessibilityAwarenessDay&lt;/a&gt; ends, I&amp;#39;ve been reflecting on all of the wonderful, talented and kind people I&amp;#39;ve learnt from over the years. I&amp;#39;ve written down the main resources I particularly love in a blog post, in case it&amp;#39;s useful for anyone else! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/kWFWwk2SFc&quot;&gt;https://t.co/kWFWwk2SFc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Beverley Newing (@WebDevBev) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WebDevBev/status/1129145780680445953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 16, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
		&lt;script async src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
	&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Accessibility Resources Published by Beverley Newing on 16/05/2019 As it’s Global Accessibility Awareness, I’m sharing a list of accessibility resources that I regularly refer to. Happy reading, watching and listening! Books 'Accessibility for Everyone' by Laura Kalbag This is a great introduction to accessibility as a topic. I highly recommend it as the first thing you read! ‘Inclusive Design Patterns’ by Heydon Pickering I am a huge fan of Heydon Pickering and his accessibility work, and Inclusive Design Patterns is a book that I regularly go back to. Brilliant introduction to accessibility and how to implement things well, with lots of HTML guidance. Webinars and newsletters A11y Weekly I now regularly look forward to these weekly newsletters! They include a collection of really interesting articles from all over the internet. I’ve learnt a huge amount from these in a very short space of time. AbilityNet Webinars The quality of these webinars from AbilityNet are amazing! These people are experts in this field and it really shows. I highly recommend giving their talks a listen to. Articles ‘What we found when we tested tools on the world’s least-accessible webpage’, GOV.UK accessibility blog GDS did a fantastic piece of research into the effectiveness of automated testing. They created a very inaccessible website and ran a variety of automated tools. Spoiler; the top tool could only get 40% of issues. The WebAIM 1 million This is an amazing and slightly horrifying study that WebAIM completed this year. They took the top 1 million websites and ran an automated testing tool over their home pages. As well as it being a brilliant piece of research, they’ve also documented how they went about it really well. GOV.UK WCAG 2.1 Primer This guide does a nice job of breaking down the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines into slightly more readable language, but still links back to them. It also contains a nice checklist of questions you can ask yourself throughout the process of building anything. 'A Responsive, Accessible Table' by Adrian Roselli Whilst this is a bit niche, I had to include it because it’s such a beautiful illustration of how complex accessibility problems can be solved really elegantly. I really love pieces of writing like this. Talks ‘Accessibility is more than just supporting screen readers’ by Seren Davies This talk is a fantastic introduction to accessibility, and how broad it is. Seren does a fantastic job of talking about different issues and some practical solutions, and also exploring the cognitive side of accessibility too. 'Screen Reader User Survey #7' by WebAIM This is a really great resource for checking that you’re testing with the most popular screen readers, and with the right browser combination. It’s worth noting though that this is a survey of everyone, and the user group for what you are creating might be different. This is just a fraction of the awesome resources out there. if there’s anything that you refer to as well on a regular basis, let me know! I’d love to hear about what you find useful too. Responses If you'd like to interact with this blog post, head on over to the Tweet about it: As #GlobalAccessibilityAwarenessDay ends, I&amp;#39;ve been reflecting on all of the wonderful, talented and kind people I&amp;#39;ve learnt from over the years. I&amp;#39;ve written down the main resources I particularly love in a blog post, in case it&amp;#39;s useful for anyone else! https://t.co/kWFWwk2SFc&amp;mdash; Beverley Newing (@WebDevBev) May 16, 2019</summary></entry></feed>